《我们的生活》前情回顾
Previously on This Is Us...
你希望跟你老公和好吗
You want your husband back?
想
Yes.
那我们就去把他找回来
Well, then we should get him back.
我觉得咱们是时候从这个地方搬出去了
I think it's time we got out of this place, you know?
搬进一个新家
Get into a home.
开始新的生活
And start a new chapter.
妈  我是凯文
Hey, Mom, it's Kevin.
我结婚了  娶了索菲  是的
I got married, uh, to Sophie, yeah.
我和索菲结婚了
Got married to Sophie.
晚餐准备
优享 食物保鲜袋
亲爱的
Babe?
我找不到
I can't find it.
这个呢  这个行吗
Hey, what about this? Will this do?
我们在第一栋房子里
We can't have our first dinner
吃的第一顿晚餐不能用毛巾布
in our first house on terrycloth.
找到了
Found it.
你看  多么完美
See? This is perfect.
到时候放在餐桌上肯定很漂亮...
It's gonna look so good on our table...
-我们的餐桌呢  -正在找
- Where's our table? - Finding table.
早上好  睡得好吗
Morning. How'd you sleep?
很奇怪  醒了好几次  总忘记自己在哪里
Weird. I kept waking up and forgetting where I was.
我也是  毕竟才刚搬进来一个月
Me, too. I mean, we only moved in a month ago.
我觉得应该还需要一段时间
I feel like it's gonna take some time
这里才会更有家的感觉
for it to feel like home.
可以把那个椅子递给我吗
Can you grab me that other chair?
可以吗  宝贝
Please, Bug?
你真觉得吃一顿豪华晚餐就能让我们淡忘
Do you really think a fancy dinner is gonna make it
凯文脱离青春期五岁就结婚
less bizarre that Kevin got married
这件事有多疯狂吗
five years after puberty?
他连存款账户怎么用都不知道
He doesn't even understand how a checking account works.
凯特  我们已经聊过这件事了
Kate, we've talked about this.
事已至此  我们只能支持他们
What's done is done. Now we just have to support them.
我觉得有个事情庆祝一下挺好的
I actually think it'll be fun to have something to celebrate.
兰德尔会带他的新女友来
Randall's bringing his new girlfriend,
米格尔会拿一瓶比较好的红酒来
Miguel's gonna bring some fancy bottle of wine...
再带个睡袋来
And a sleeping bag.
怎么  反正他也总来
What? He's here all the time.
他帮我们跟房产中介砍价  还修好了排水沟
He also talked the Realtor down and fixed the gutters.
至少应该邀请人家来吃顿饭
So I think that at least deserves a dinner invitation.
我去上班啦
I'm off to work.
对了  你的工作如何
Hey, how is work, by the way?
你似乎很喜欢
You seem to really be liking it.
还行吧  有点无聊
Yeah, it's okay. A little boring.
这家店有人上班吗
Hey, does anyone actually work here?
-快去  -我知道  这就去
- Go. - I know, I'm gonna go.
有人吗
Hello.
有  来了
Yeah. Coming.
宝贝  慢点吃
Baby, slow down.
我得看一遍科学课演讲
I have to go over my science presentation,
校对一下英语论文  复习西班牙词汇
proof my English essay, and review my Spanish vocab
都得在上学之前
before school.
好  "咀嚼"西班牙语怎么说
All right, well, what's Spanish for "Chew"?
-masticar  -那就好好做
- Masticar. - Then do that.
早上好  吃早餐的美女们
Good morning, my breakfast beauties.
准备好度过精彩的一天了吗
Who's ready to own this day?
你今天早上出门很早
Hey, you were out early this morning.
-我都没看到你  -我看到了
- I didn't even see you. - I did.
没错  因为我们是早起的鸟儿
That's right. 'Cause we're early birds.
有虫吃
Getting that worm.
跑了十英里  时间破了记录  不值一提
Ten miles. Best time. No big deal.
十英里  怎么  你在训练跑马拉松吗
Ten miles? What are you, training for a marathon?
我就是感觉很好  就继续跑了
I just felt good and I kept going.
黛佳  吃麦片吗
Hey, Dej. Cereal?
1/3玉米片  2/3麦圈
One-third Corn Flakes, two-thirds Cheerios,
是你喜欢的配方
just like you like it.
你觉得给我一份麦片  我就能原谅你们
You think cereal is gonna make me forget
把我当成无法自主决定跟谁在一起的孩子吗
you treat me like a child who can't make her own decisions about who to date?
是这么计划的来着
That was the plan.
好吧
Okay.
你得想个好点的计划了
You're gonna need a better plan, man.
是啊
Yeah.
凯特
Hey, Kate.
你得告诉我  你给宝宝准备了什么礼物
Okay, you have to tell me what the baby gift is.
不行  会破坏惊喜的
I don't. It'll ruin the surprise.
是一匹小马吗
Oh, is it a pony?
兰德尔  我喜欢小马
Huh, Randall? I'd love a pony.
或者  或者热水浴缸
Or a, or a hot tub.
给一个婴儿吗
For a baby?
我可不知道
Look, I don't know.
皮尔森家的男人们以大手笔出名
The Pearson men are known for their grand gestures.
真的是一切皆有可能
It could be literally anything.
-是啊  -与此同时  我得走了
- Yeah. - In the meantime, listen, I got to go.
我要去锻炼了  好了
I'm off to the gun show. All right.
爱你  再见  兰德尔
Love you. Bye, Randall.
不是小马   也不是热水浴缸
It's not a pony or a hot tub.
但是我和凯文一起送的
But it is from me and Kevin.
他逼我答应这么跟你说
He made me promise I'd tell you that.
尽管是我的主意  一切都是我做的
Even though it was my idea, and I did everything
他什么都没做
while he did nothing.
等礼物到了  你先打给我
So you call me first when it gets there.
好吧  对了...
Okay. Hey, um...
我担心小凯
I'm worried about Kev.
他买了一辆房车
I mean, he bought a trailer?
在宾夕法尼亚州
In Pennsylvania?
静悄悄的  挺好的对吧
Quiet's nice, huh?
本来是挺好
It was.
跟我爸一起长大是什么感受
So... what was it like growing up with my dad?
跟我说一件他小时候的事
Hmm? Tell me a story about his childhood.
他喜欢冰淇淋
He liked ice cream.
是个好故事
Yeah. That's a good story.
是个很好的故事  那我补充一下
That's-that's a great story. Uh, I'm gonna expand on that a bit.
我记得我小时候  我爸回家时
I remember when I was a kid, my dad used to come home,
有时候会带几盒纸盒包装的冰淇淋
sometimes he'd bring these, uh, these cartons of ice cream.
就是带纸板边的那种
You know, the, the ones with the cardboard sides
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
你把它们折下去
that you'd fold down,
中间只摆个冰淇淋砖块
leaving just a brick of ice cream?
翻译     青椒   春天里的小熊   InArance
总之  他会...
Anyway, he'd, um...
-从这切吗  -就这里
- Right there? - Right there.
他就像切蛋糕一样切冰淇淋
He'd cut it like it was a cake.
翻译     学术男优   Tracy-旋子   台风16   夏摩夕
切一大块
Big old cut, oh!
翻译     包子欣   Funky   capitaljack
校对     Funky  青椒   红枫
天啊  我真的好喜欢他那样
God, I really loved that.
时间轴     大葱  cciJQ
什么都不想说  好吧  很好
Nothing. Okay, great.
后期     8T
你期待
Mm. You, uh, you looking forward
总监     红枫Gabriel
-今天的冰球比赛吗  -本来是的
- to the hockey game today? - Yeah, I was.
-好吧  -但后来觉得不是很想去  所以
- Yeah. - But then I remembered I don't really want to go, so...
今天的比赛他们会向退伍军人致敬
Listen, they're honoring vets at tonight's game.
他们会请卡西迪到冰面上
They're inviting Cassidy down on the ice,
比赛和致敬安排在一起
it's a whole thing.
而且我可能已经告诉她
Plus I might have told her
我会帮她赢回她丈夫
I'd help her win her husband back.
你...
You... have
跟别人的关系真奇怪
strange relationships with people.
这可能是你对我说过的最好听的话
Might be the nicest thing you ever said to me.
议员先生
Councilman.
酒局放我鸽子的人来了
Ah... there's the man that stood me up for drinks.
感谢你见我
Thank you for meeting me.
那晚的事  我深感歉意
I'm really sorry about the other night.
我也不想错过上好的苏格兰威士忌
I hate missing a good Scotch
和关于贵族化的良性辩论
and a healthy debate on gentrification.
鉴于你显然有更重要的事要做
Well, it didn't sit too well with a few councilmen
其他几位议员有些不满  但之后
that you obviously had better things to do, but we
德尔弗里斯科餐厅的牛排安抚了我们
consoled ourselves with steaks at Del Frisco's afterward.
不好意思  是我女儿学校打来的
Ah, excuse me, this is my daughter's school.
喂  是的
Hello. Yes.
您跟我太太说过了吗  她没接
So, did you talk to my wife? She didn't?
好吧  我马上就过去
Okay. Um, I will be right there.
议员先生  我很抱歉  但我得走了
Councilman, I'm so sorry, I have to go.
我女儿急性焦虑症发作了
Um... my daughter had a panic attack.
我们的生活
第四季  第五集
餐前小点
好了  现在两条腿已经
Okay. Two of the legs are now
稳稳地装好了  只要找到剩下的两条就好了
officially attached. We just have to find the others.
那口大锅去哪儿了
Where is the big pot?
没有大锅  我做不了千层面
I can't make lasagna without the big pot.
亲爱的  那就有问题了  因为我饿死了
Oh, baby, that's a problem, because I-I'm starving.
我想起来  我可能忘了
And I think, I think I might have forgotten
把大锅打包了
to pack the big pot.
来个餐前小点垫垫怎么样  好心的先生
How about an hors d'oeuvre to tide you over, good sir?
谢谢
Thanks.
祝你有个好胃口
Bon appétit.
希望三文鱼不会太难嚼
I hope the salmon's not chewy.
不  挺好的
No, it's good.
你不喜欢三文鱼
Uh, it's okay if you don't like salmon,
或对它过敏  也没关系...
you know, or are allergic...
我完全忘记问你有没有忌口了
I totally forgot to ask about dietary restrictions.
我喜欢三文鱼
Uh, I-I like salmon.
你们觉得呢  我该在小凯和索菲来之前
What do you think, guys? Should I, uh, open the wine
打开葡萄酒醒酒吗
and let it breathe before Kev and Sophie get here?
饮用前让红酒接触空气以提升口感
好吧  我去开瓶醒酒
Yeah. I'll open the wine and let it breathe.
我忘拿配菜茴香了  稍等
I forgot the dill garnish. Hold on.
没错  加点配菜就能让
Ah, yes. Because a garnish will
凯文结婚这事显得不那么出格
make it less crazy that Kevin got married.
-凯特  别这样  -我说得没错
- Kate, come on. - It's true.
我在记录房子里需要修缮的地方
I keep a list of things to fix around the house
因为我妈独自一人  需要帮助
'cause my mom needs help now that she's alone.
其实她并不是独自一人
Oh, actually, she's not alone.
有我一直陪着她
I'm here all the time.
好了  配菜来了
All right, I got the garnish.
这提醒我了
Oh, that reminds me.
我也带了份乔迁礼
I brought a housewarming present.
什么
What?
为了今晚
Tonight.
其实它背后有个故事
Um, there's a story behind it.
别担心  它...
Don't worry. It's...
怎么  你们都讨厌辣酱吗  还是...
What, d-does everybody hate hot sauce, or...?
不不不
No, no, no. Um...
只是...
It's just that, uh...
杰克生前吃什么都要加辣酱
Jack used to put hot sauce on everything.
我爸生前也超爱辣酱
Uh, my dad loved hot sauce, too.
爱到去哪都随身带着一瓶
So much so that he brought a bottle of it wherever he went.
是用来送人的  但那其实不是礼物
Um, as a gift, but it wasn't actually a gift.
他只是想确保自己总能吃到辣酱
He just wanted to make sure he always had hot sauce.
他吃鸡蛋要加
Um, yeah, he put it on-on eggs
汉堡也加
and put it on burgers.
有一次他甚至往冻酸奶上淋了辣酱
Um, one time, he even put it on Froyo.
所以在他去世之后
Yeah, after he died,
我也开始拿辣酱当礼物
I started bringing it as a gift, too.
-谢谢  -没事
- Well, thank you. - Mm-hmm. Yeah.
一定是他们
Oh, that must be them.
这太别扭了  不是吗
Hey. This is weird, right?
-妈  -看看你们俩
- Hi, Mom. - Look at you guys.
我们顺着妈妈的意思就好
Let's try to be supportive for Mom.
他们来了
There they are.
我的天呐
Oh, my goodness!
请进  请进
Come on in. Come in.
老婆大人  你想进屋吗
Uh, wife, would you like to enter?
是的  老公
Yes, husband.
好嘞
Okay.
我们现在就是这样进屋的
This is how we enter buildings now.
-好吧  -就这样
- Okay. - Yeah.
这一出确实挺别扭的
Now, that's weird.
谢谢
Thank you.
你想聊聊这事吗
You want to talk about it?
因为我其实略知一二...
'Cause I know a thing or two about...
不想  谢谢
Please, no.
其实没关系的
You know, it's okay.
我也经历过
Happens to me, too.
有时根本毫无来由
Sometimes it just comes out of nowhere.
比如当我的生活发生了太多事时
Like when I have a lot of stuff going on in my life.
我甚至不知道自己濒临崩溃
I won't even know that I'm feeling that way,
结果压力就在一瞬间爆发了
and then it just catches up to me all of a sudden.
宝贝
Hey, baby.
我立刻从工作室赶回来了
I left the studio right away.
-你还好吗  -是的  她没事
- Are you okay? - Yeah, she's okay.
护士说她有点呼吸困难
The nurse said she had a little trouble breathing
心跳加速
and a rapid heart rate.
可能是由焦虑引起的
Probably brought on by some anxiety.
是这样吗
Is that what's going on? Huh?
-你感觉焦虑吗  -我不知道
- Feeling a little anxious? - I don't know.
-或许吧  -这说得通
- I guess. - It makes sense.
最近发生了很多事  新学校  新朋友
There's a lot happening. New school, friends.
你也因为成绩给了自己很大压力
You put a lot of pressure on yourself with your grades.
-你这点应该随我  -别说了
- I think you get that from me. - S-Stop.
别说什么我像你
Stop saying I'm like you.
我不想和你有任何相似之处
I don't want to be anything like you.
你难道不需要
Hey, don't you, uh, don't you have one of those
欢迎各位老兵
越南棒球帽之类的戴一戴吗
Vietnam baseball hats you could wear or something?
凯文  来这里和去听音乐会不一样
You know, it's not like it's a-a concert we all went to, Kevin.
不不不  我只是觉得如果你让别人看到
No, no, it's, it's-- I'm just saying, like, it would be nice
你之前服过兵役会比较好
if other people could recognize you for your service.
你明白我的意思吗  那样比较符合
You know what I mean? That's sort of what this whole thing
整场活动的氛围
is all about.
你知道怎么会比较好吗
You know what would be nice?
我一口气喝十瓶啤酒
If I could just drink, like, ten beers in a row,
这样就可以熬过这个活动
you know, just to get through this.
别紧张  我开玩笑的
Relax. I'm kidding.
我更喜欢喝威士忌
I prefer whiskey.
你来了
You made it.
整场活动看来不错  恭喜啊
Hey, congrats on the whole, uh, you know, your whole thing.
-我想是的吧  -嗯
- Oh. I guess. - Yeah.
马蒂的爸爸要来参加这个典礼  所以...
Um, Matty's dad's coming to the ceremony, so...
好的
Oh, okay.
闭嘴
Shut up.
他只是努力当个好爸爸  带着他的儿子来看
He's just being a good dad. He's bringing his son
-大家为他的妈妈鼓掌  -妈妈
- to see people clap for his mom. - Mom!
-凯文  -你好啊  小家伙
- Kevin! - What's up, buddy?
-你来啦小帅哥  -要不来击个掌
- Hi, bud. - What do you say? Get me up high.
好样的  跳得真高
There it is. Nice vertical.
感谢你能来
Thanks for coming.
爸
Dad!
爸  这是凯文  他是不是
Dad, this is Kevin. Isn't he cool
-像我说的一样酷  -过奖  你知道吗
- like I said he was? - Nah, come on. You know what?
我只是给这孩子买了包奇巧  幸会  瑞安
You buy a kid one Kit Kat. Good to meet you, Ryan.
真高兴终于见到被我九岁的孩子
Ah, glad to finally meet the adult man
一直称为他最好的朋友的
that my nine-year-old son keeps saying
成年男人了
is one of his best friends.
-好了  走吧  -好的
- Okay. Come on. - Okay.
没人比你跟别人的关系更奇怪了
You really do have the strangest relationships with people.
沙拉
我找不到桌子的第四条腿了
I couldn't find the fourth table leg,
所以我们只能靠着牢靠的桌腿吃饭了
so we're just gonna have to eat on the strong corner.
宝贝  你现在都怀着
Babe, you're already cooking three babies
三个小孩了  你不需要做这些的
in your belly, okay? You don't have to do this.
这是我们在新家的第一晚
It's our first night in our new home,
我想让一切井井有条
and I want everything to be just right.
-好的  -给
- Okay. - Here.
开始准备你的沙拉吧
Start on your salad.
小凯
Hey, Kev.
你吃出沙拉的配方了吗
You recognize the salad recipe?
是埃默里尔·拉加西的
It's Emeril Lagasse.
-谁  -埃默里尔·拉加西
- Who? - Emeril Lagasse, you know,
那个口头禅是"嘭"的厨师  我们去年
the chef that goes "Bam." We watched him together
一起看的
all last year.
对对对  "嘭"
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Bam.
-嗯  就是他的配方  -是的  绝对是
- Yeah. This is him. - Yeah, totally.
太棒了
Awesome.
所以你们俩怎么结婚的
So how come you guys got married?
是因为一个征兆
Mm. It was a sign.
和他们说说
Tell them.
我走在纽约街头
So, I'm walking down the street in New York.
那天很美
Beautiful day.
我想到和在索菲一起就觉得很幸运
I'm thinking about how lucky I am to be with Sophie,
我抬头一看  恰好看到前面的电影院
and I look up and I happen to be in front of a theater
正在放映《公主新娘》
playing The Princess Bride.
我们最喜欢的电影
Our favorite movie.
-是啊  -对
- Yeah. - Yeah.
是的
Yeah.
所以这就是那个征兆
Oh, so, then, that was the sign...
不是  并不全是
No, not all of it.
不不不  在路对面  有个教堂
No, no, no. Um, across the street, there's a church
响起钟声  然后大约两秒后
that starts ringing its bells and, like, two seconds later,
-一个街头小贩走过来卖东西  -卖戒指
- a street vendor walks up selling... - Rings.
-手镯  但肯定算是珠宝了  -是的
- Bracelets, but definitely jewelry. - Yes.
对  是这样
Yeah. Um, and, yeah.
在那一刻  我意识到
In that moment, I just realized that, um,
我一秒都等不及要开始和她生活在一起了
I couldn't wait another second to start our lives together.
所以...
So...
我又怎么能拒绝呢
And how could I say no to that?
你们想看结婚照吗
You want to see the wedding photos?
好啊  想看
Yes. Please.
当然了
Of course.
我去杜恩·里德便利店买了相机
I picked up the camera at a Duane Reade
在去教堂的路上
on the way to the courthouse.
-是拍立得啊  -我要看
- Oh, Polaroids. - Ooh, I want to see.
你们瞧瞧
Look at these.
我看完了传给你们
Oh, I'll pass them around.
我去开门
I'll get it.
你怎么来了
Hi. What are you doing here?
我不想留你独自应付晚上的饭局
Well, I didn't want you to have to go through tonight alone.
就从你的入职申请表上找了地址  我...
So, just got your address off your application and I, uh,
还顺手采了你邻居的小雏菊  就过来了
picked your neighbor's daisies and, uh, here I am, so...
好浪漫
Oh. That's so romantic.
还有点瘆人
And a little creepy.
-正是我啊  风格多样  -宝贝  谁啊
- That's me, just all together. - Hey, Bug? Who is it?
你确定要加入吗
You sure you want to do this?
-宝贝  -十分确定
- Bug? - Oh, absolutely. Yeah.
-好吧  进来吧  -没问题
- Okay. Come on. - Definitely.
各位  这是我同事
Everyone, um, this is my friend from work.
我是马克
Oh, I'm Marc.
我是凯特的男朋友
I'm... Kate's boyfriend.
对
Uh... yeah.
你和卡西迪经常去看各种比赛吗
You, uh, you and Cassidy go to a lot of games?
她打冰球的时候肯定很好玩吧
She must be fun at the hockey games, huh?
我从来没去过  我不喜欢冰球
I've never been. I hate hockey.
没错  冰球最讨厌了
Yeah, yeah. Hockey sucks.
太差劲了
Just awful.
我要走了
I'm out of here.
你说什么  你还没...  庆典
What do you mean? You're not-- the ceremony
还没开始呢
hasn't even started yet.
尼克叔叔
Uncle Nicky. Hey.
-在这里我不大舒服  凯文  -借过下
- I don't feel good here, Kevin. - Pardon me. Hey.
那你要去哪儿
Where are you, where are you gonna go?
你打算去酒吧吗
You gonna go to a bar?
没有  就想换个地方待着
No, I just need to be somewhere else.
-那我跟你一块去  -不用  我想静静
- Well, let me go with you. - No, alone.
我没事  拜托了
I'm fine. Please.
兰德尔  你给我赶快打电话过来
Randall, you have to call me back and tell me
告诉我那惊喜大礼什么时候送到  好吗
when this present is getting here. Okay?
我和这个睡着的小宝贝在屋里守着
I'm trapped in my house with a tiny sleeping baby
还有只尿急的狗狗
and a dog who has to pee.
你们再怎么大手笔
There's just no way that this grand gesture
也不值得我这样耗着啊
is going to be worth it.
回我电话  拜拜
Call me back. Bye.
终于到了吗  我的天呐
It's here? Oh, my gosh.
好吧
Okay.
你就是我的大礼吗
Are you my present?
我不知道你说什么呢
I have no idea what you're talking about.
没有  我就是来看外孙的
No, I came to see the baby.
好吧
Okay.
-很棒  -所以你最喜欢的乐队
- Very cool. - So, your favorite band
叫谦虚老鼠
is called Modest Mouse?
华盛顿摇滚乐队  风格独特多样
等下  那是乐队名吗
Now, wait a minute, is-is that a band
还是个腼腆的卡通人物
or a shy cartoon character?
不是  其实这名字来源于
No, it's actually from
弗吉尼亚·伍尔夫的一篇短篇小说
a Virginia Woolf short story.
英国女作家  意识流文学代表人物
对  而且
Uh, yeah. And,
那个主唱  他是从
and so, like, the lead singer, uh, like, he got started
录制一些疯狂的试验性歌曲起步的
by recording just, like, these crazy experimental songs
用着失真效果器在他的答录机录歌
with a distortion pedal on his answering machine
类似这样的  然后...
and stuff like that, so, you know...
...挺酷的
...it's pretty cool.
-非常酷  -是很酷
- Very cool. - So cool.
你们觉得马克怎么样
So, what do you guys think of Marc?
感觉他对冷门音乐轶事很着迷啊
Oh, he seems like he's really into obscure music facts.
这也是他工作的一部分  凯文你觉得呢
That's kind of his job. Kevin?
他对你来说太老了
Uh, yeah, he's too old for you.
-真的太老了  -他才23岁
- Definitely too old for you. - Uh, he's 23.
爸爸比妈妈还大六岁呢
Dad was six years older than Mom.
你们怎么能不喜欢他呢
How do you guys not like him?
是吧  他对你们那么友善
Okay? He was nothing but nice to you.
我个人是没什么意见...
I personally don't have a problem...
我说不上来  就是直觉吧
I don't know, it's just a feeling.
就像有次外婆让我们尝一下蜗牛
Like that time Grandma wanted us to try escargot.
我们尝都不用尝
You know, we didn't need to try it
就知道不爱吃那东西了
to know we didn't like it.
马克给我的感觉就像蜗牛
Marc is escargot.
-你们觉得贝丝怎么样  -她很不错
- What do you guys think about Beth? - She's great.
真的吗  太好了
Yeah? Cool.
不  说真的  她简直完美
No, actually, she's perfect.
她眼睛上还有个美人痣  我以前
She even has a beauty mark on her eye. Didn't know
都不知道真的有这东西  不过好漂亮
that was a thing until now, but it's adorable.
-不像马克  -凯特  拜托
- Unlike Marc. - Kate, come on.
你要让我昧着良心回答你吗  我好喜欢马克
You want me to lie? I love Marc.
-他简直是我新欢  -你  算了算了
- He's my new favorite. - You-- no, no. You know,
我根本不在乎那个  凯文
I don't even care about that, Kevin.
你结婚居然都没告诉我
You got married without telling me. Okay?
-我们难道不是无话不谈吗  -你知道吗
- I'm supposed to be your person. - You know what?
-我们是临时起意  -这件事我赞同凯特
- It was spontaneous. - I'm with Kate here.
居然是拍立得照片
Polaroids?
发生什么事了
What's going on in here?
凯特很生气
Kate's freaking out.
不  凯文  我没生气
No, Kev, I'm not freaking out.
我只是  我不想坐在桌前
I'm just, I'm not gonna sit here
假装承认你那荒谬的婚姻是真的
and pretend that your ridiculous marriage is real.
这位大哥  你叫什么来着
Man, so, who are you, again?
那你说  凯特  那我们该怎么做
I don't know, Kate, what are we supposed to do?
-待在这一直难过吗  -兄弟  别这样
- Stay here and be sad all the time? - Hey, bro, come on.
-怎么了  不是要袒露心声吗  -别说了
- What? We're being honest, right? - Guys, stop.
你太自私了
You are so selfish!
-够了  够了  -我们本该出席你的婚礼  凯文
- Enough. Enough! - We should have been at your wedding, Kevin.
今晚是我们一家人在新家
It is our first night as a family together
度过的第一个晚上  我花了几周时间
in our new house, and I have spent weeks
组织这场聚会  只为了做到事事完美
getting this place together so that it would be perfect.
因为今天是我们向前迈的起点
Because this is where we move forward.
我们围桌而坐  面前摆着纸巾和餐具垫
This is where we sit around a table with napkins and placemats
欢笑着庆祝  再一起吃游乐鸡
and laugh and celebrate and eat Cornish game hens.
所以我对天发誓  我们一定要做到
And so help me, God, that is what we are gonna do:
向前迈
move forward.
其他都不重要  虽然我用的锅小了
And it doesn't matter that I didn't have the right size pan
导致游乐鸡都挤在一起
and that the hens are all squished together
所以上面烧焦了下面还是生的
and they're burnt on the top and raw on the bottom.
凯文不记得埃默里尔  无所谓
It doesn't even matter that Kevin doesn't remember Emeril,
我只收到了婚礼的四张拍立得照片也没关系
or that I have four whole Polaroids of your wedding.
你们都给我精神点
So pull yourselves together,
假装喜欢烧焦半生的食物
pretend you like burnt raw food,
闭嘴乖乖回到座位上坐好
get your whiny little asses back out in those seats,
然后享受这顿该死的晚餐
and enjoy my damn dinner.
主菜
宝贝
Babe.
不不不  再等会  马上好
Oh, no, no, no. Wait for it, wait for it.
你真是天才
You're a genius.
没错  我知道
Yeah. I know.
我来帮忙
Here. I can help.
看看这铺上多好啊
There we go. Look how nice that is. Huh?
什么味道
What's that smell?
你把烤箱里的东西拿出来了吗
Did you clean the oven out?
我以为你拿了
I thought that you did.
什么
What?
天啊
Oh, God.
杰克
Jack.
天啊
Oh, man.
宝贝
Wow, baby.
看起来依然不错
Still looks good.
好吗
Okay?
我们吃这个会生病吗
Can we get sick from this?
味道很棒
So good.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
请起立
please stand
一起向布莱德福特郡的比赛冠军们致敬
as we honor Bradford County's Heroes of the Game.
请把热烈的掌声
Please give a round of applause
送给美国空军少尉艾伦·埃利斯
for U.S. Air Force Second Lieutenant Alan Ellis.
以及美国海军陆战队上士卡西迪·夏普
And U.S. Marine Corps Staff Sergeant Cassidy Sharp.
最后  让我们表达对美国海军上士
And finally, let's show our support for U.S. Navy Chief Petty Officer
古提瑞兹的敬意
Jon Gutierrez.
帮忙跟卡西迪说一声  我有事要离开
Hey, can you tell Cassidy I had to take off?
她什么时候带马蒂回家都行
She can bring Matty home whenever.
感谢你们为我们国家的自由
We thank you for your service and dedication
所奉献和付出的一切
to our nation's freedom.
她已经待在屋里一小时了
Yeah, she's been in her room for an hour.
我们得跟她谈谈
We got to go talk to her.
我试试烤奶酪能否让她愿意开口
Let me see if grilled cheese can get her to talk.
她很爱吃我做的烤奶酪
You know, she loves my grilled cheese.
威尔金斯很生气你又爽约
你没事吧
You okay?
没事  我很好
Yeah. I'm fine.
从小到大  我没接触过跟我有相似基因的人
Growing up, I never shared genetic traits with anyone I knew.
我们俩有了孩子以后
And when you and I had kids,
我迫不及待地想看看她们从我这里遗传到了什么
I couldn't wait to see what they got from me.
她们会有可爱的耳朵  能卷舌头吗
Would they have cute ears, be able to roll their tongues?
有焦虑症和惊恐发作
Having anxiety and panic attacks
是我对自己最不满意的地方
is the thing about myself that I like the least,
我却传给了她
and I passed it on to her.
我好恨自己把这个传给了她
I hate that I gave this to her.
医生怎么说
What did the doctors say?
他们想让他再留院观察一晚
They want to keep him another night.
看看他是否能适应药物
see how he adjusts to the medication.
这次的问题肯定累积一段时间了
This must have been building for a while.
当他感觉有些事情开始失控时
He feels things getting away from him,
就会开始
and then he...
非常努力地想要掌控事态
works really hard to rein 'em in.
比如花更多时间在办公室  在健身房
Like more time at the office, more time at the gym.
他开始不断给自己压力
And then he just pushes himself
崩得越来越紧...
harder and further and...
我应该注意到这些症状的
I should have saw the signs.
我年轻的时候受过这个罪
I had a tell when I was young.
真的吗  你也有焦虑症吗
Really? You had anxiety, too?
那时还没有焦虑症这个名字
Back then they didn't have a name for it.
他们说我  "脆弱"  "敏感"
They said I was "Fragile" and "Sensitive."
但当它发生时  我以为我要死了
But when it was happening to me, I thought I was gonna die.
不过我妈妈会帮我渡过难关
My mother would help me through it, though.
她会在杯子里装满苏打水  然后告诉我
She'd fill a glass with seltzer water and tell me
我的脑海就像是这些气泡在跳动
the inside of my mind was like the bubbles bouncing around,
想要跑出去
trying to get out.
我们会一起看着这些气泡消失
And we'd watch together until those bubbles settled.
我最终也会安定下来
Eventually, I would settle, too.
贝丝  在我所有能遗传下去的事情中
Beth, out of all the things I could have passed down,
我最不希望的就是这个
I hate to think that it was that.
葡萄酒
宝贝  来吧  会很棒的
Babe, come on, it's gonna be perfect, it's gonna be perfect.
好吗
All right?
其实呢  我觉得烟熏过后
All right? You know, I think the smoke
会给它一种正好的山核桃味
gave it a nice hickory flavor.
-山核桃千层面  -山核桃千层面
- Hickory lasagna. - Hickory lasagna.
你...
Hey, are, uh...
你没事吧
are you okay?
我是不是努力过头了
Am I trying too hard?
我们...
Are we...
我们无法痊愈了吗
are we unfixable?
也许这次伤痛...
Maybe this loss is just...
太大了
too big.
你说呢
You know?
我觉得吧...
Uh, you know, those...
你这些问题听起来呢
those sound like questions that can only be answered
似乎只能用我带来的葡萄酒回答
by the wine that I brought.
不
No.
十年来我几乎没喝过酒
I've barely had a drink in ten years.
你很幸运
Well, lucky for you, over the course
在我的无数个无聊约会中
of the many, many boring dates that I've been on,
我掌握了很多葡萄酒知识
I have learned a lot about wine.
好吧
Okay, fine.
好的  这个...
Okay. Uh, this...
是一瓶蒙塔希诺·布鲁奈罗
is a bottle of Brunello di Montalcino.
他们称它为意大利葡萄酒之王
They call it the King of Italian wines.
用百分之百的桑吉奥维斯葡萄酿造
It's a hundred percent Sangiovese grapes
它们只生长在托斯卡纳的蒙塔希诺镇
grown only around the Tuscan town of Montalcino.
-蒙塔希诺  -蒙塔希诺
- Montalcino. - Montalcino.
很好  那个产区太小了
Very good. Now, the region is so small
不能每年都生产顶级葡萄酒
that they can't produce a top vintage every year.
葡萄成熟的季节必须是完美的
The ripening season has to be perfect.
如果天气不那么完美...
And there's nothing they can do if the weather...
就不行
won't cooperate.
也许太热了  也许太冷了
Maybe this year is too hot. This year's too cold.
他们...
They, uh...
他们必须有耐心
...they have to be patient.
他们只能耐心度过不好的年份...
They have to wait out the bad years...
并且一直坚信明年会好的
believing that there is a better year coming.
而明年总会好的
And it always is.
谢谢
Thank you.
-把酒给我吧  -好的
- Now give me that wine. - Okay.
谢谢你送我
Thanks for the ride.
-没事  -我以为我们会...
- Yeah. - I thought we'd be...
像一家人一样一起吃晚饭
having dinner together afterwards as a family.
我真蠢
I'm so stupid.
你不能只是希望婚姻能够一切顺利
You can't just wish a marriage into working out.
事实是
The truth is,
我觉得也挽回不了什么了
I don't think there's much to save.
别说爱了
Forget love.
我认为他根本不喜欢我了
I don't even think he likes me.
跟我来
Come with me.
-妈妈  我不想谈...  -过来
- Mom, I don't want to talk about... - Come on.
我需要你下楼
I need you downstairs.
-能等一下...  -不能
- Can it wait for just a s...? - Nope.
你俩都不喜欢你们身上的一个共同点
You two don't like this thing you have in common.
我理解你们
And I get that.
确实很可怕
It's scary.
但这也造就了
But it also made three
世界上我最喜欢的三个人
of my most favorite people in the world who they are.
威廉也会为事情焦虑
William would also get anxious about things.
他...  很敏感  有艺术细胞  也关心他人
He was... sensitive and artistic and caring.
但是关心和担心之间有一条微妙的界线
But there's a fine line between caring and worrying,
有时这条界线会变得模糊
and sometimes that line gets blurry.
从我见到你父亲的那一刻起
From the moment I met your father,
他就一心想让身边的所有人
he was obsessed with making everything okay
都过得舒服
for everybody else.
这虽然需要一些时间来适应
And that took some getting used to,
但我很爱他这一点
but I loved him for it.
因为这意味着他很在乎
'Cause it meant he cared deeply.
现在  你从你父亲那继承了一些东西
Now, there's some things you get from your dad
你需要摸索着去适应
that you're gonna have to navigate around,
但同时也有一些馈赠
but there are some gifts, too.
你做任何事都倾尽全力
You give everything your all.
你是个了不起的姐姐
You're an amazing sister
女儿  朋友和学生
and daughter and friend and student.
听我说  无论现在是什么问题
Now, look, we're gonna get whatever this is
我们会掌控的  好吗  相信我
under control, okay? Believe that.
但我不允许你
But I will not have you talking ill
对我在世界上最喜欢的三个人言辞不敬
about three of my most favorite people in the world.
不行  绝对不行
No way, no how.
你听明白了吗
Are you hearing me?
如果事情变得难以承受...
And if it ever gets to be too much...
就等一下...
Just take a minute...
...让你的情绪气泡平息
...and wait for the bubbles to settle.
威廉教的
William.
上周艾希莉想知道
Last week Ashley wanted to know
我是否觉得德尚很性感
if I thought DeShaun was hot.
我当时就应该出柜的
I should have just come out then,
就像我计划的那样
like I'd planned to,
但是...
but...
相反  我却说是的
instead, I said yes.
现在惹出来一堆麻烦
And now it's gonna be a whole thing.
确实很难办
That's a lot.
但我们能够解决的
But we can figure it out.
谢谢
Thanks.
当初  我和你们父亲搬进新家的那晚
So, the night your father and I moved into our house,
我也做了一顿丰盛的晚餐
I made a fancy dinner, too.
当然  最后我把千层面烤糊了
And, of course, I ended up burning the lasagna.
所以我们不得不打开窗户
So we had to open the window
把厨房里的烟都排出去
to let all the smoke out of the kitchen.
就在我们坐下来吃饭的时候
And just as we were sitting down to eat,
一只鸟从窗户飞了进来
a bird flies in through the window.
现在  这个故事的重要细节是
Now, the important detail of this story is that
-你爸爸害怕鸟  -特别害怕
- your dad was terrified of birds, - Terrified.
-超级害怕  -是的  绝对的
- Terrified. - Yeah, he was.
所以...
So...
他跑出房间...
he runs out of the room...
-杰克  -然后又跑回来
- Hey, Jack? - and he runs back in
拿着一个网球拍
with a tennis racket
还有一个枕头套  然后他说...
and a pillow case, and he goes...
别担心  我会抓住它的
Don't worry, I'll catch it.
他一定把鸟吓坏了
He must have freaked the bird out,
因为鸟儿开始...
because then the bird starts...
朝他扑过去  在房间里追他
diving at him and chasing him around the room.
你父亲发出了我听过的
And your father made the most ridiculous squealing sound
最好笑的尖叫声
I've ever heard.
然后他想躲开那只鸟
So he's trying to get away from the bird
想用网球拍去保护我...
and protect me, I guess, with the tennis racket...
等等  它去哪儿了  它去哪儿了
Wait, where did it go? Where did it go?
就在那里  快看  看
Right there. Look, look, look.
杰克
Jack...
不知怎的  我们把千层面弄翻了
And somehow we knock over the lasagna.
小贝
Bec?
然后我们就开始哈哈大笑
And we just started laughing.
从那一刻起  那晚变得十分完美
And that's when it became the perfect night.
因为我们就这么顺其自然了
When we just let it be what it was.
我们不能只怀着悲伤的心情想念他
We need to be able to think about him and not only be sad.
我们要能够坦然地聊起辣酱的事
We need to be able to talk about the hot sauce.
对吧
Right?
他和那顿晚餐有着异曲同工的完美
He was perfect the way that dinner was perfect.
他让我们...特别幸福
He made us... so happy.
我对你们的期望也不过如此
And that's all I want for you guys,
我只希望你们幸福
is just for you to be happy.
那我们来举个杯吧
Then, let's have a toast.
-来吧  -为幸福干杯
- Please. - To happiness.
-为幸福干杯  -为幸福干杯
- To happiness. - To happiness.
-也敬凯文和索菲  -对
- And to Kevin and Sophie. - Yes.
-恭喜  -恭喜
- Congratulations. - Congratulations.
敬凯文和索菲  干杯
To Kevin and Sophie, cheers to that.
干杯
Salud.
好啦  这顿饭难吃死了  我承认
All right, this meal was disgusting. I admit it.
-谁还饿着呢  -我
- Who's still hungry? - Me.
-我  -我
- Me. - Me.
-我也是  -我真的...
- Me, too. - I am tru...
披萨
不用找钱了
You can keep the change.
谢谢你
Thank you.
披萨来啦
Pizza...
-我来拿他的东西  -谢谢
- I'll get his, uh, stuff. - Thank you.
应该的
You got it.
给你了
Here you go.
-谢了  -没事
- Thanks. - Yeah.
今晚的冰球比赛上
You know, your wife was, uh, she was being honored tonight
你太太的服役被致敬了
for her service at that hockey game.
她知道你会来的时候特别激动
Man, she was excited when she found out you were showing up.
如果你只是来傻站着  全程盯着手机
If you were gonna stand there and stare at your phone all day,
你还过来干什么呢
why'd you bother coming?
行吧
Okay.
跟你聊得很开心
That's good stuff, man.
我15岁那年遇到了她
I met her when I was 15.
我往生物教室走的时候
I smashed into her in the hallway
在走廊上撞到了她
as I was walking into biology class.
我当时就知道
And I knew,
我在她书掉到地上之前就感觉到了
I knew before her books even hit the floor,
我遇到了我最喜欢的人
I had just met my favorite person.
你刚刚说的那场典礼
That, uh, that ceremony that you're talking about
它所致敬的东西  毁了我全世界最喜欢的人
honored the thing that broke my favorite person in the world.
我只能盯着手机看  要不然
I was staring at my phone because otherwise
我就要在我儿子面前哭了
I would have started openly weeping in front of my son,
他现在不需要我的眼泪
and that's not what he needs from me right now.
对不起  我...我不知道这些
I'm sorry, man. I-I... I didn't know.
你离我老婆远点
Stay the hell away from my wife.
他睡了  我周四再来接他
He's out. I'll be back for him on Thursday.
好
Yeah.
怎么了
What?
他还喜欢你
He still likes you.
没事  我没喝酒
It's all right. I'm sober.
好的
Okay.
我不喜欢讲故事
I'm not a storyteller.
也不喜欢和人接触
And I don't like people.
就连你  我都不是特别喜欢
I-I don't even like you very much, and, uh,
而你是过去20年来和我走得最近的人
you're the closest person I've been to in the last 20 years.
你爸爸并不是
You know, your father wasn't the, uh,
第一个这么做的人
first person to do this.
那个小把戏他是跟他爸爸学的
Uh, he learned that trick from his father,
也就是你爷爷
uh, your grandfather.
那家伙混蛋一个
That man was a bastard,
但时不时地...
but every now and then...
他也挺有趣的
he could be kind of fun.
他的做法是...
Yeah. What he'd do was...
...他会把纸盒四边折下来
...he would fold down the sides of the carton,
于是冰淇淋就会看起来像个大蛋糕
so that it looked like a, like a big cake.
然后他会拿把刀
And then he'd then get a knife
在冰淇淋上比划
and just wave it over the ice cream.
然后他会问
And he'd, he'd ask, uh,
"你今天有多乖啊
"How-how good a boy were you today?
你是有点乖
Were you kind of good?
还是非常乖"
Or were you real good?"
看你怎么回答
And depending on the answer,
他就给你多大一块冰淇淋
that was how big a slice you got.
那么...
So...
你今天乖不乖呢  凯文
How good were you today, Kevin?
我今天好像把我叔叔惹生气了
I think I annoyed my uncle today.
除此以外  我感觉我还挺乖的
Other than that, I think I was pretty good.
那就给你
Well, then, you get
一块还挺好的冰淇淋
a pretty good slice of ice cream.
而我非常乖
I've been very good.
我要送给你们结婚礼物
Uh, I need to give you your wedding gift.
-我希望是一个爆米花机  -我希望是现金
- I hope it's an air popper. - Oh. I-I hope it's cash.
-凯文  -借过
- Kevin. - Excuse me.
不  是一首歌
No, it is a song.
送给这对新婚夫妇
For the newlyweds.
来自一部叫《公主新娘》的电影插曲
From a little movie called The Princess Bride.
*来啊  亲爱的  我给你讲个故事*
*Come, my love, I'll tell you a tale*
*有关一个男孩和一个女孩*
*Of a boy and girl*
*还有他们的爱情故事*
*And their love story*
*他爱她有多深呢*
*And how he loved her*
*情深似海*
*Oh, so much*
*她魅力四射*
*And all the charms she did possess*
*这都是真情实感...*
*Now, this did happen...*
-当心一点  -那是我们的旧钢琴吗
- Just-- careful. - Is that our old piano?
*当时一切都很单纯...*
*Things were not so complex...*
皮尔森家的男人们又完成了一次大手笔
The Pearson men nail another grand gesture.
*她走在路上*
*Ground that she walked*
*他凝视着她的眼睛*
*When he looked in her eyes*
*他从此深陷不能自拔*
*He became obsessed*
*我的爱就像是童话书里的故事...*
*My love is like a storybook story...*
这是中央C音
That's middle C.
没错  这就是最基础的乐音
Yeah, that's your home base.
找到了这个音  你想弹什么都能弹得出来
You know where that is, you can go anywhere.
没错
Yeah.
*我的爱就像是*
*My love is like*
*童话书里的故事*
*A storybook story*
*真实得如同我此时的感受*
*It's as real as the feelings I feel*
*真实得如同我此时的*
*It's as real as the feelings*
*感受...*
*I feel...*
-我给苔丝找了一位心理医生  -很好
- I found a therapist for Tess. - Good.
应该会对她很有帮助
I think that'll be really helpful for her.
另外...我也给你找了一个
And... I found one for you, too.
我不需要心理医生
I don't need a therapist.
我很好  这些年来都没有感觉这么好过
I'm good. Best I've been in years.
但你一直都在拼命地加班
But you've been working crazy hours
一天跑十英里  而且还经常抖腿
and running ten miles a day and constantly bouncing that knee.
你想想看  不用非等到
You know, you don't have to wait
事情把你逼崩溃了  再寻求帮助
for it all to come crashing down to get help.
知道你觉得我要崩溃了  我真"开心"
Glad to know you think I'm gonna crash.
还记得吗  你第一次崩溃的时候
You know, when you had your first breakdown,
你以为那会是唯一的一次
you thought that was gonna be the only one.
这些年来你强挺着筹划准备所有事  宝贝
All these years of just managing it and making lists, babe...
现在资源更丰富了  有受过专业训练的人
We have resources now and people who are trained
他们很擅长解决这方面的问题
to deal with this kind of stuff.
很感谢你这么担心我
I appreciate your concern.
-但我很好  -好吧  我很担心
- But I'm fine. - Okay, I am worried
如果再出一件什么大事  你就会...
that we are just one big emotional thing from this...
贝丝  我很好
Beth, I'm fine.
*我的爱就像是童话书里的故事*
*My love is like a storybook story*
*但也真实得如同我此时的感受*
*But it's as real as the feelings I feel*
*我的爱就像是童话书里的故事*
*My love is like a storybook story*
*真实得如同我此时的感受*
*It's as real as the feelings I feel*
*真实得如同我此时的感受...*
*It's as real as the feelings I feel...*
怎么了  宝贝
What's wrong, Bug?
什么
What?
你爸去世后的那一年里
I was trying so hard to hold it together
我太拼命地想要让一切如常
that year after your father died.
我太想相信你们几个孩子都很幸福
And I wanted to believe so badly that you kids were happy.
我很抱歉没看到当时都发生了什么
I'm so sorry I didn't see what was happening.
我也没有看到
I didn't see it, either.